Lucas Cavalcanti Rodrigues

Data Engineer

Links

Github Linkedin Stackoverflow

Technical Skills

OS

GNU/Linux, Windows

LANGUAGES Python, Java, Javascript, Rust, R

FRAMEWORK flask, node.js, pandas, matplotlib, statsmodel, scikitlearn, sympy

DATABASES SQLite

CLOUD GCP

OTHERS

Airflow, Markdown, Git, Vim, VS Code, Jira

Analytical Skills

Data Structures
Algorithm
OOP
Probability
Data Analysis
Econometrics
Machine Learning
Agile methodologies

Education

2017-2021 PHD ECONOMICS Universidade de São Paulo

2013-2014 MR. SC. IN ECONOMICS Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora

2009-2012 B.A. IN ECONOMICS Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora

Summary

I'm a professional with over 7 years of experience working in different areas of the data lifecycle, such as analytics and infrastructure. A significant part of this experience is due to my work as an economist, both in academia and the private sector, where I worked with statistics, econometrics, and machine learning. Since 2021, though, I have focused on data engineering and infrastructure. I have over 4 years of experience using Python, in addition to having working knowledge of a number of technologies, such as Google Cloud, Airflow, Bash, Java, SQL, among others. I'm also a highly motivated professional, with strong organizational and multi-tasking skills, who always aim to add value to the business and the teams I work with.

Experience

AUG/21- Data Engineer

DP6

I work on collecting and structuring data obtained from customer interaction channels such as mobile apps and websites *Python, Javascript, Google Analytics, Firebase, GTM, Data Studio*

Ост/20-Jun/21 Researcher

Parceiros da Educação

Bom Retiro · São Paulo - SP

lucas.ecomg@gmail.com

+55(11) 95600-2307

30 years

I was responsible for developing and implementing the ESG Racial Equity Index (IEER), a metric used by several companies in the Brazilian private sector to assess and monitor the status of racial inequality among their employees. In addition to develop the index, a by-product of my doctoral thesis, I was also responsible for the data infrastructure used to compute the index. The infrastructure was built using resources from the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).

Python, Pandas, GCP, Cloud Storage, Big Query, Flask

JUL/17-JUN/21 Researcher

Universidade de São Paulo

During my PhD in economics I worked with historical census data, in addition to other official statistics, to analyze access to basic education, land and the labor market among Brazilians and immigrants. In the analysis, a series of techniques was used, such as fuzzy matching, machine learning and econometrics.

Python, R, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Statsmodel

JAN/16-JUN/17 Data Analyst

CAED

I contributed to public policy reports directed to the subnationals Departments of Education by carrying out the statistical analysis of microdata. In these analyses, among other techniques, I used statistical methods such as Factor Analysis, Index Construction and Linear Hierarchical Models.

SPSS, Microsoft Office

Other Employment

2016-2017 Professor of Economics (1 year) 2021-2021 Data Consultant (6 months)

UFJF

MPT